All right welcome back we're live twenty-fifth
...build I'm here with some people tell us your names and what
you do your jim I'm scott and,
I work it's partly that the apparently you go all the time
works with your to pulley fixes yummy okay I agree I like to
...damien I...I'm scott and I work in acinet...
app service I believe it's your called...in the office...and user out
...and I work on entity framework by the way live questions
...just stepped up...a framework questions please bring them up I mean I'm sure he
...answer so when I started out the...radio...every snow over I had
some confusion about dot net framework client profile what is how is that all set up
...educate me and then we'll talk about dot net core and what that means raised on it?
Okay,...was...all as a and we've got really cool...thank you very much incrementally should
...the only framework when you compile your application you have to compile against
a set of assemblies right when you add reference those things exist and you
...api...within those you get intel's...while ago we introduce the
concept of reference assemblies which represent the platform that you want to compile again so,
for example, silverlight...windows phone or wherever it is dot net is running you want
to say I'm going to compile against that set of things because when you're in visual
studio actually composite against windows phone itself, you know, running fine your
compiling against a set of assemblies that represent that world...those a reference assemblies think of them
is contracts so we have reference assemblies for each set of whatever your dot net
things you have on those platforms dot net framework has a set of reference assemblies that represent the dot
net framework on windows dot net client profile which was something we did back in the
dot net for timeline also had a set of those things as well and now that we have
something like dot net core and we have...and we have eight-minute
...type of things we have reference assembly sets all of those as well and moving forward in the
dot net world you can basically...always be compiling against a promise
of what you're actually going to be running against eventually that portable class libraries which we've had
...users will work the same way when you say I want to portable classed library that works on silverlight
...of what five windows...you're building a common
subset of reference assemblies always seems get sort of munged download into a profile number
and there is on your hard drive a set of as a reference assemblies
full that profile number and that's what you compile again.
So, let's talk about the new asp dot net.
And, this is going to be like a tough question it feels like we're
starting again but not starting again it's new but it's not new
help me understand is it is it like a brand spanking new saying that we
need to relearn or is it part of something we already now tell me about that...
So, it's a brand new thing that looks a lot like the old thing got.
It's concept compatible so if you're building nbc application yes there still are
controllers there still are actions there still is raiser but,
if you if you go deep down the stack there is no system web got
...that's an interesting distinction right but if you already building
...you should be happy movie over the...you know,
I went from a regular car to a hybrid car the mechanics
...to relearn how the previous works but it still drives the same got it
so it yes stuff underneath...for the most part I can still get point-to-point b with the concepts
and the techniques that I'm used to using but I can also bringing new techniques
open-source javascript libraries open-source task runners I've got modularity
they didn't have before...got choices across platform...still dot net, yeah,
just like dot net...windows phone is dot net
...windows desktop as dot net on system web all based on
...we know it now is net and we have dot net nascent five and new single
...next that is also dot net depending on what you classify is dot
net represents a lot of things like languages compilers list of
this and I'm sure there was a lot of discussion before this happened as to why what are the
...benefits of doing this for people to move forward
into a speed on it seems like there's tons of cool stuff but I want to tell us about why you would go to that's
some of the big benefits the to...we want to have the ability to be side-by-side
...everyone have the problem again where customers to
...and...application put on a server and they're like I don't have the right version of dot net on the server
or I'm afraid to put a new version about in the server because it might break something else on the server
got it we don't what those problems...people building
...applications that was a huge.
Thing we're looking for with
...five another one was we know that you know, when a world where there's,
you know, in as your cloud we have linux we have windows and we want is
panetta run all everywhere that you can
...measure cloud...I mean to me it seems really good because it now dot net is
reduced to like we're going to put a specific assembly for dot net in the been
folders that kind of how it works...okay though I mean I don't it is improve
...to the point where you've got your app your user
your process gets to pick what like in our demo if you take a look at the deep dive
and is net he opens up a command prompt and switches from one-dot
...dot net core framework to another
so I asked him can you open up to have this run beta three and that run beta for this
...five or whatever you make your own personal private version of the course
a larger and run it all locally and the...with...did with
...hunter we with and published...
app two-a memory stick picked a laptop a random laptop out of the audioeyes
...though...off there and just work because it's all private look and that
...on every...it did nothing on the machine touch no system thirty-two...no registry
...runs off the memory stick so that means that say just-released you're just
finisher application you're getting rate...a new version of dot net comes out and say it's
...what you'll one out there and then when you want to upgrade refine it's now all of
...all the been and director...the clear
...talking about on the core as well as on a very clear...if you run on dot net framework which is what
ships with windows you always run under the contracts...the behaviors all done...framework other
...there's...resolution rules that you really compact a affect dot net
core as we get all these new capabilities in this new...been at five can...target both of the...by will...when
...building eighty-five that you can choose to run on budget four-six or...five-point
to...four-point-five for five-two or you can run on core...core
...your choice and there are some implications of those choices net core eleven
...framework today is over a hundred megs so dot net
core is not this doesn't have all the same stuff that button framework...the is the
same asp net...like to be clear impedance and that five?
Runs on for framework you want to use it on four-point-six on the machines in the
...that you already have it will work just fine and it is not there's not like to versions of...
net right there's one there's the one and...can run in multiple...that's really cool so let's
shift now to entity framework seven is this is a new thing is
...is a...work six-plus more staff is it
also about...about it take everything we just said about isp dot net and swap out the
named entity framework and you basically in the same but so it's concept
compatible if you're interacting with the top-level api it looks exactly the same under the
commas completely new core with ripped everything...replacing it with stuff that is light-weight
and extensible it can run on for dot net...can run on dot net core and,
...can run on phones yet another tablets yet so windows ten universe
...platform entity framework works there and...also done some demos obviously
...get cross platform with dot net as well now done demos with...that running even...iowa's
simulate this site by fantastic so that must have been some core meetings.
What...going to now with entity framework seven why was the decision why did you decide to rip it out
and start again...have concept compatible maybe not bottom compatibles on something we've been talking about doing
for quite a while now ever since we did a four-point-one we've talked about could we replace the core of ef and
it just never made sense because it's going to be a little bit of pain for some people...
upgrade but then we've got isp dot net coming we need to run on this new dot net core
...this point the all code base we had it's just not really feasible to go
and achievers things and site
...seven and with everything else...happy across microsoft with
...platform dot net core with isp dot net five and all that stuff it was the right time to go and
do this like...so here's a question and I think from
...and I think this is a good it'll bring into relief a little unit jonha yeah,
sorry john will have sharply support as a first-class language and
...it sorry yes sowe into that is we're still trying to finish esp net so one thing that
...understand is we're like a step behind visual studios schedule so like they just
...the...this week and we're still beta for right so,
we think that will be one milestone beyond visual studio right now our goal is just
to get csharp...so we're open to things like...sharper open to things like the ...
right now our first goal get csharp shipped and, then we'll start working and having
...model put in...net so we can go plug-in other languages twitter really
...that when visual studio releases we will not release
will be probably and rc when visual to be...releases and,
then on update one of visual studio will be our team because...needs to be done these the
...sp right we're going we're going to a correct we're not going to rush this thing we solve a lot of work to do there was we
had questions from customers this week...of...them stuffing how do I do x with based...five and, you know,
what I to look at them site we don't know yet we haven't quite got to that's on the list of things in the back
...we...design yet because we're still sorting out some of the core elements, you know,
I honestly prefer the way we're doing things now because it's better to
the open say this is what we're doing we're still working on it take a look at the build this whole thing
it be the wrong thing when it comes out okay so now...question and I think this
...to release a little bit how we think about things asp dot net or
...makes you happy I met him and his convince me on sp net
...try if you like it there's lots of different things there's web api
there's nbc...signal our for real-time
...webpages which is a lot like
phd of your into php lars who asked the question go up to magic
...get hub and look at many blog
...a great example of a php style application with the our of
lambdas and csharp and...the clr that you look at that and that's the language of your
soul and you should use it is ph spears language of your sold and knock yourself out use
...make sure that your deploying on as...using visual studio...
Other...is visual studio I mean we have one of the best ideas on the
...and it supports days net you can also use
...code if you're more of a text that are kind of person we have great tooling
...net probably more than phd has there's another question that gets into the architecture motivates
...what's the relationship between could tunnel owen and esp done...thought ever
...at me again I can so could tub you can think of...a...of...because I was the
code name that we use for a bunch of projects that we did of the last couple years signal
I was built on web api to can be hosted on
...could...was a experiment in some ways it was what would happen if we re
imagined how...could run outside of the context of ios?
So, we implemented things like authentication with on top...implemented like
I said self-service signal those type of things all incense...the open windows interfaces
with dot net which is a layer of abstraction that allows anything that conform so that
...contract whether it be a web server...a web application sitting on top of
...web application framework to work together so if you're web server talked owen
...web application framework talks and then you could run the...framework on that...so,
the...was our effort to sort of implement owen...more strongly types sort of
...microsoft the way what we learn from...we took over into a
...five and indeed the card...project kate that would be...project cake was kind of out let's take a
...and then.
We like...and re imagine everything I'm...little bit...a whole lot all the way down to dot net let's not even a
...windows let's assume we can run
...or linux what...we have to change make that happen so,
that was kind of a point in time...was a point in time the last...and now we're moving on
to a lot of...you know,...even there so if you're running web api to or signal
are three those are both running on photon...today if you're if you're building and acinet for
ex app you're actually using castano on those two platform they were they were already written in a
way so they could actually run self host outside of is in outside of
...so if a company as an investment in owen.
Pipelines and components what...they do with those things when the...five is
...is a feature-based...five we're not built on a on so you can take
...compliance server and run...five on top of it if you have
...middleware which effectively is just lambda...a delegate...the contract you
...that into the eigth-bit on that five http pipeline vier
...okay so we support...as a feature well-built directly on top of all got it
okay so let's talk about any frameworks I feel like relieving you out that's what are the main
differences that you would say top-level between
a framework six and eighty frameworks seven as far as
the developer experience and maybe even as far as how the plumbing I think,
yeah, absolutely I was going to say one of...big decisions we had to make
was in...any from we kind of had to ways of modeling we had the...designer which was
this boxes and lines over the top of an xml file and we had code
first which is a bad name it's actually just code based modeling where I can express my
modeling code which could be creating a database from the model
or I could have a code model-based on existing database so
...have seven way removing support for the xml file format and just focusing on the
code format now people get stressed out when I hear this but, what we've seen is that people
especially with big applications in the enterprise scenario they think that xml
...work metaphorical and actually try the code base format works a lot better if a team
environment's for doing self-control merges everything split up into separate files the
same as all the rest of the coding your application instead of storing everything in one massive xml file
dot so the designers...a big of a any other differences, yeah, so,
I think the top-level api is the same but once you drill into the core things get pretty different so if
you're writing code that wants to look at the metadata model that represents
classes and how...to the taiwan everything things start to look a bit different
there now they look different because they're a lot better if anyone...to use the metadata api in
the fsix it's horrible it's extremely on intuitive
...seven we bit the bullet and we actually...it usable but that means it's
...the...of learning to do that all right so moving back to...dot net there's a lot
of terminology...dn...dn you there's a bunch of other things can you can you
help us understand all of those tools what they do and what...talk
...at all like...like those things if we really well and we did an hour
...part one another...apart too and we feel that the
story arc that we built in those talks?
We didn't know it would work I mean honestly, you know,
you put together talk you put a lot of work in a talking it worked those are
now all the canonical two hours of if you wanted to hours of training on is
...thrive that's it could stop it really is a good start but the
short the short is dn vm is the version manager
...you pick which dn x you want
ok dn axes the execution environment that gets it all started.
In dn you are the utilities it's everything else spilled package
...up got it so if you really
want to get a really good deep dive this one says what's the name a session the first loans
...ally and then divx basement...sounds good all right so they've
asked a question is dot net core going to be faster the full frameworks it's only ten percent in
...of the simple answer is no size and...not...correlate right but
that said we are doing a lot of work amazement five as part of this move...net core and on
...framework still to most of the...gains if they're going to be any are actually
...itself not in dot net core versus dot net framework it's the same...it's the same
seal arts of sm version see a lot but there isn't anything magically done...to make
your application many times faster we are doing performance testing the big areas of
...I can tell you now that the throughput system we have in the memory
use testing we've done for al test cases we have a now equal
tool better than those apps running on nbc five and dot net for ex we've really may
...in startup one of things acinet was never particularly good at what you could file
...web which had not much code but a bit and then you...it takes like many
seconds so that app to boot right...and run on the server we
have drastically improve that so over a period of four weeks we got...five in as
a down from a cold startup time of about fifteen seconds to less than three while
still think that there...maybe like thirty percent chunks that we can grab as well as one of the stuff that we can
...a lot of that is tricks a lot of that is no now we have a global packages locations of the packages
don't live with the app necessarily anymore so we can prakash all the most popular
...packages on the server a whole bunch of other tricks like that so
...now modular...so you can turn
...office...if you want so if you want to go try to do something that's just going to
go talk to a socket you don't need routing you don't need
...you don't need all that stuff you can turn on is often much
...so that's a area we can increase the speed of a...nets and we dramatically reduce the
...yep as well just every requested in system web is
...got of stuff we build-up we build-up six...in acinet
five so that's a massive reduction in memory for every request comes through less work
in the garbage collector and most net applications garbage collecting is
...packer performance so here's an interesting question from...says less...
dot net five says the fundamental http iness of the stack
...http...as well we don't have a should be
...right now unless you run on a iso windows ten right the way
should be to covers a lot of things it's like a channel multiplexing it's a should be had a compression
it's push promises new credential type stuff you'll get some of those things for free depending on the web server
...because it's implemented the server...other stuff requires api and,
...working on that as we go the moment but fundamentally someone still has a
...open someone is still positive http messages as they come in and presenting
...using...and response...a web socket you're still having to
...thing that says I want to treat this incoming request as a web socket handshake
requests upgrade me to a binary sort of thing that's...the same case it is...enough five-zero
...there's...question there's been a fair amount of community feedback around for a
bundling and minutes occasion are...just going to stick with goldman grunts well
it's gulp right algonquin support...crime or is it going to be something that you do internally
visual studio...running the underlying question would be what if you like
...magnification that's the essence of the
...I think so I think that you within peat write a piece of middleware that bones...that yes you
...all you could write a piece of you attack open...that, for example,
you could do it as part of the build process you could have something that folks into the dane x build step
...package...and...it using dot net instead of gopal...right now
and now templates gulp is what we set up by default by the time we are tm will have
...unification set up in there as well but,...we're open to community feedback we're going to look at what
...and...and how they and this is a challenge like people are saying well like
...that's great but what about the prescription and I know that it's on it's unusual maybe a little
bit uncomfortable sometimes it microsoft doesn't give you the prescription but sometimes it's like well, you know,
if you use advil that is good for these kinds of things and aspirins good for those
...and we're hearing a...and we are going to put something in the default
prescription yes isn't right for everybody...there will be a default
prescription but I'm just pointing out that there's more choice than ever before
and I think a little bit of...if I may be so bold as to say that the community and the user of
...and that is going to have to think about what's right for them and, you know,
having runtime...medication might be great for small application if you're doing this
...a large enterprise...large...you're probably not going to do that you're going to do it build time so
you're going to have to think about what's right for you and I think what's fun about is
...at five is the choice is now possible...like with any from you can plug
...put in post crescent like that you want,...usually oils actually going to say all
this stuff we've been talking about applies to entity framework as well right like it's good to have a default
description in fact in...framework we didn't do a good job of that before we'd be like you can do
anything just pick whatever modeling so, are you want and now we're saying a
little bit more opinions as what to do by default but let's also open everything up so you can plug-in whatever you want
to agree point of...stuff in the framework seven also can talk to know sequel type stores as well so he's
guys...demos where he's actually shown...talking to asher table storage yep
non we've done some...talking work...cash as well so what we're doing there is not
trying to build some magic framework that hides...data store because that looks great on stage
...a works when you actually try to...right I like the pragmatism there yet awesome
...so we're trying to take...stuff that applies all data stores like that in an of
this stuff that's relational specific put that in a relational specific library dot so
...just a question ok...
dot net five be able to run on seven that's just...I mean...I mean...there
...is nine-point-five or what I think maybe...having my days been
at five and it'll run on windows server two thousand eight up so the answer is...because I
...seven-point-five is the minimum and that's on twenty up to the seven-point-five and up
...iso correct okay so another one from jason will sp dot net
identity be changing with the new asp dot net already has so the templates as they are right now
and twenty fifteen ossie use hp that
identity free basically identity three is built on top of dot of the next mobile
basement five to work with a...five applications you can't use identity three in
eight-minute for ex just like you want...signal...or...on top of a
acinet for exorcism...has nudity stuff is taking advantage of the...
parts of our stack like...injection and stuff like that...got so john are will
epidemic continue to open up more ways for developer to tap into the pipeline?
Absolutely I mean more than ever all than ever we will I mean...will be more first
...zipping private...internal so there's a few things that are private right now,
for example,...that's the part of
...lives in is that boots at the next application that's currently private we haven't done the work
zero ok...yet...talks that's...five...that's...boot the see
...iso vs...command line I guess the only significant pop that we have that
...we might be running around inside the object browser like that's...
microsoft in the plane is open it up as...haven't got...there's lots of work to do and,
we'll get to that...the...you'll see is...a lot of the a lot of the libraries we have now...nbc will have an
internal name space so it's not actually internal its mocked public but we
namespaces internal and say this is intended for internal use but we'd love to public because
...might be something useful there in the...ads internal icon...it will now
hate call it but don't call if you want support...can call if you want it feels like more
choices is the...here...go ahead with...just going to say with that internal thing...doing the same thing
...entity framework is everything is public by default but we are setting aside parts of the
stack in the internal...saying we're not guaranteeing that we want break this vitally releases
site so just to finish up ...has a really good question is there going
to be migration slash help between the fsix you
have seven asp net asp net five.
When you're outside you have...first...
...will be guidance on how-to-do-it I would say that we're not going to recommended all apps
built on it entity framework six upgrade...seven who definitely get two-stage in the future
we site you have seven is recommended for new applications but it's not going to
make sense upright everything was still doing patch releases and...releases...thought and now twenty-second it's going
to be the same thing guidance they will not be a tool tell you right now there's not going to be...tool you point your
embassy five application and it operates mpc six differe we didn't have one that you point embassy
for operated embassy five of us throughout but they will be plenty of god's
...probably make a new project yes and start bringing peace...
Well, it feels like we're just more open about what people can do people have more choice and I think
...that's happiness all around thanks so much for spending some time with
the will catch you guys after the right take care.